（キバ）おい…　ネジ大丈夫か？
Hey!
Neji, are you all right?!
（ネジ）あぁ…　大丈夫だ。
Yeah...
I'm okay.
無理すんなって。
Don't overdo it.
敵の感知は
あんたの眼だけじゃなくて→
Your eyes aren't the only things
that can track the enemy.
俺の鼻もある。
I have my nose.
ここは俺に任せて→
Leave this to me and
あんたは医療部隊のところへ
行ってこいよ。
get yourself checked out
by the Medical Corps.
ちょうど　各部隊の
中央後方にテント村がある。
There's a medic tent in the rear center
of every company.
座標は…。
The coordinates are...
（赤丸）クゥーン。
（長門）あんた…
どこまで暁のことを知ってた？
How much did you know
about the Akatsuki?
（イタチ）お前よりは
知っていたつもりだが…。
I thought I knew more
than you did, but...
（長門）結局　俺もあんたも
人に利用された忍だ。
Ultimately, we're both shinobi
who were used.
（長門）お互い持っている
この強すぎる瞳力のおかげでな。
Thanks to our powerful
Visual Prowess.
今回も
術者に後回しで動かされてる。
This time too...
The user of this jutsu is using us.
ペイン…　お前の六道の力。
Pain...
With your Six Path's Rinnegan
and my Mangekyo Sharingan...
輪廻眼と俺の万華鏡写輪眼。
この２つの瞳力さえあれば→
we could do anything.
ほぼ　なんでも
出来ると言っていい…。
（イタチ）術者のヤツはこのタイミングで→
The jutsu user intends to
take advantage
俺の幻術の力を利用するつもりだ。
of my genjutsu power
when the time is right.
イタチ…　確かにお前は暁において→
Itachi, you have always been wrapped
in darkness,
闇の中の忍だったからな…。
even when you were
part of the Akatsuki.
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
I was asleep all this time, I kept quiet all this time
zutto nemutteta zutto damatteta
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I can see something far away
tooku ni nanika ga mieru
something more important now than studying
benkyou yori mo ima taisetsu na mono
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I think we can find it
mitsukarisou nanda
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
see, you can overtake the future
mirai wa hora oinuite
this ship can really fly through the sky
hontou wa sora toberu fune
Medic Ninja in Danger
ぐっ。
（シズネ）医療上忍の方２人。
I need two Jonin Medics
over here, please!
こっちに手を貸してください。
今から蘇生処置を行います。
We have to resuscitate now!
早く！
（２人）はい！
Quickly!
– Right!
（トントン）ブーブー！
だ　大丈夫か？
こんなに乗せて…。
Are you sure you can
carry this much?
ブーブー！
止まってください！
Halt, please!
これより我々感知タイプの忍が→
Under orders from HQ,
本部を通して
あなたのチャクラを確認します。
we Sensory-type shinobi will
have to verify your chakra!
それまで
中へ通すわけにはいきません！
We will not allow you to pass
until this is done!
あぁ…　わかってる。
Sure, I understand.
さっさと確認してくれ。
Hurry and get it over with.
（サクラ）包帯を…。
I'll bandage it...
はい…　これで大丈夫！
Okay...
That should do it.
ありがとう…。
Thank you...
お大事に…。
Take care.
では　次の方　入ってください…。
Okay, next please.
ネジさん！
Neji!
とりあえず
外傷の手当てはしておきました。
I've taken care of all
your external wounds.
すまない…。
Thanks.
今のうちに
ゆっくり休んでいてください。
Please get some rest,
while you can.
特に　その眼を…。
Especially your eyes!
あまり　酷使しないように…。
You shouldn't overuse them.
そうともいかない…。
That's easier said than done.
俺の役目は
誰よりも早く敵を識別し→
My job is to discern things
faster than anyone,
それを部隊に伝えて
戦闘を有利に展開することだ。
and notify HQ, in order to improve
our chances in battle.
そのためには
この眼に働いてもらわなければ。
To do that, I have to put
my eyes to work.
わかってる。
I know that.
でも…　せめて　ここでは…。
But while you're here...
ありがとう…。
Thanks.
さて…　次の巡回のテントは→
All right, the next tents on
our rounds are F5 through G3.
Ｆの５から…　Ｇの３か…。
どうしましたか？
Is something the matter?
痛みが引かないようでしたら…。
If you're still in pain...
え…？
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
た…　大変だ！
B-Bad news! Toyosa, Takemaru,
and Hino are dead.
トヨサとタケマルとヒノの３人がやられた！
何者かに暗殺されてる！
なんだと！？
Someone has assassinated them!
What?!
いったい　どういうことです？
What's going on?
どうやら　敵のスパイが
潜り込んでいるらしい…。
A spy has infiltrated us.
あぁ…　上忍医療忍者ばかりを
狙っているところをみてもな…。
They're targeting Jonin Medics.
しかし　どうやって？
But how?
ここへ入るには
厳しいチャクラでの本人確認が→
In order to get here,
everyone's chakra undergoes
strict verification.
徹底されているはずだ。
変化の術程度では　当然無理…。
It's impossible with a simple
Transformation Jutsu.
連合の忍でなければ入れない…
それは確実…。
And you cannot get through here
unless you're a shinobi of
the Allied Forces.
とすると　その連合の忍が→
Which means...
that an Allied shinobi is being
manipulated by a jutsu.
術で操られてる
可能性が高いわね。
It's highly probable.
相当の術よ。
It's a formidable jutsu.
どうしたんだ　これは？
ネジさん。
What happened here?
Neji...
なるほど。
I see...
連合の忍しか　ここに
いないということになれば→
If there are only
Allied Force shinobi here,
見分けるのは難しい。
they'll be hard to distinguish.
誰が犯人かわからない。
We can't tell who the suspect is.
今もこうして
皆　立っているが→
We're all standing
around right now,
隣のヤツが　犯人かもしれない
という疑念が→
and it could be any one of us.
And this is sure to breed
suspicion among us.
互いの不信を生むことになる。
それが敵の狙い。
That's what the enemy
is hoping for.
医療忍者は　今や
戦術をなすための要です。
We Medical Ninja are critical for
our battle strategy to succeed.
穢土転生の不死を
相手にするには→
There's no way you can confront
私たち　医療忍者の
バックアップなしでは考えられません。
the undead from the Reanimation Jutsu
without our back up.
こんなことで
ここが　マヒしたら→
If we're paralyzed now...
夜明けの開戦で
不利になってしまう。
It will ruin our chances in the battle,
that starts at dawn.
俺が犯人を見つけ出してやる。
I'll find the killer with
my own eyes!
この眼にかけて！
とにかく
何があっても負傷者を→
In any case,
no matter what happens,
放っておくわけにはいかない。
治療は　続けていく。
we cannot ignore the wounded.
We'll continue our treatment.
ただ皆
各々　気をつけてくれ。
But we must be extra careful.
医療上忍は特にだ。
Especially the Jonin Medics.
さてと…。
Now then...
そろそろ
巡回診察の時間だな。
I-It's time to go on rounds.
ああ…。
Y-Yeah...
♪～
お　お前と初めて
会った場所ってどこだっけ…。
W-Where did I... first meet you?
Huh?!
あ！　いや…　お前を
疑ってるってわけじゃないんだ。
No... Listen, it's not like
I'm suspicious of you.
決して　疑ってるんじゃないぞ。
Of course not.
ただ　ただな…。
疑ってんだろ！
It's just... just...
You are suspicious of me!
うわっ！
ん？
なんだ　あんたか。
びっくりさせないでくれよ。
Oh, it's you.
Don't scare us like that.
それより
春野サクラはどこにいる？
Say, have you seen
Sakura Haruno?
何かあったのか？
Is something wrong?
少し気になるヤツがいてな。
I got suspicious about someone.
そいつを　つけていたんだが
見失った。
I was tailing him, but lost him...
よく考えれば　サクラのまわりを
ウロウロしていた感じがしてな。
Thinking back, I get the feeling that
he was hanging around Sakura.
サクラは　３番のテントにいる。
Sakura is in Tent 3.
怪しいヤツ…。
いったい　どんなヤツだ？
What does this suspicious guy
look like?
そうだな…。
Well...
♪～
たしか…。
I could've sworn...
っていうより　俺だ。
Well, it's me.
あなたでしたか。
Oh! It's you.
傷　まだ痛みます？
Is your wound still bothering you?
あ　いや…。
Oh, no... It's fine.
もう大丈夫です。
じ　実は…。
私を治療してくれたときから→
A-Actually, ever since you treated me...
あなたのことが　どうしても頭から
離れなくなりまして。
I haven't been able to
stop thinking about you.
これって…。
ラ　ラブレターってやつです。
What is this?
I-It's... what they call a "love letter."
次　戦争へ出て生きて帰って
こられる保証はありません。
When I go into battle again,
there's no guarantee that
I'll come back alive.
だから…。
So...
ありがとう　でも…。
Thank you.
But... I'm already in love
with someone.
私には　もう好きな人がいるから。
そうですか…。
Oh, I see...
やっぱり　それって木ノ葉の…。
I guess he's probably... a Leaf.
って　フラれた男が
あなたの好きな人を→
Well, a rejected man has no right
to pry into who you love.
あれこれ詮索するのは
ほんと　無粋ですよね。
わかりました。
僕はもう行きます。
I understand. I'll go now.
ごめんなさい。
I'm sorry...
うまくいくといいですね。
I hope it all works out.
あなたが好きになる人だ。
If you love him...
きっと　すてきな
いい人なんでしょうね。
he must be a great man.
ハァ…。
♪～
どういうことだ？
What's going on?
術者は　なぜこうまでして
敵と俺たちの接触を避ける？
Why is the jutsu user
going through such pains
to prevent us from
encountering the enemy?
お前の幻術も
使わないつもりか？
He's not going to use
your genjutsu, after all?
It's night. Stalemate.
夜は　睨み合いの続く
静かなる戦い。
マダラには　俺たちを動かして
静寂を破る前に→
Before he uses us to
break the silence,
何らかの手があるのだろう。
Madara has something up
his sleeve.
この　穢土転生は
マダラが新しく組んだ輩の術だ。
This Reanimation is the jutsu
of Madara's new ally.
マダラ自身の作戦が　前もってあった。
It did not figure into
Madara's original plans.
そういうことだな。
だろうな。
Is that it?
Probably.
大丈夫か？
ネジさん。
You all right?
Neji...
落ち込むのも　無理はない。
It's easy to get discouraged.
目に見えない敵が
どこに潜伏してるのか→
We don't even know
who we're fighting.
わからないからな。
そうね。　気をつけなきゃね。
I know, we must be careful.
ああ。
Yeah...
なぁ　本当に
医療忍者部隊のところへ→
Are you sure you don't need
to go to the Medical Corps?
行かなくて大丈夫なのか？
Cut it out, Kiba! I said I'm fine!
しつこいぞ　キバ！
俺は大丈夫だと言ってるだろう！
白眼の使いすぎで
フラフラだったくせによ！
You overused your Byakugan
and can barely stand!
後輩の前で　無理しても
かっこつかねえって。
So don't bother showing off
in front of your subordinates!
うるさいぞ　キバ！
（赤丸）クゥ～ン。
Shut up, Kiba!
なんだよ！
犬と人を見間違えるほど→
What the hell? You're so weak,
you can't tell the difference
between a dog and a man!
弱ってんじゃねえか！　仮にも
あんたの持ち味は　視力だろ！
And your Visual Prowess is
supposed to be your specialty!
（シノ）ヒナタ　お前も　無理をするな。
Hinata, don't overdo it either.
なぜなら
俺の奇壊蟲が広範囲に散り→
That's because I have spread
my Parasitic Insects
throughout the area,
to look out for the enemy.
敵を見張っている。
（ヒナタ）
シノ君　心配してくれてありがとう。
Shino, I appreciate your concern.
でも　私も頑張りたいの。
But I want to give it my all!
This is a war to protect Naruto!
この戦いは　ナルト君を守る戦争！
絶対に負けられないもの！
We cannot lose!
ところで　サクラ
シズネ隊長は　今　どこにいる？
By the way, Sakura...
Where is Captain Shizune now?
え？　何か
手がかりでもつかんだの？
Huh? Did you figure something out?
ああ　少しな。
Yeah... a little.
どんな些細なことでも
連絡はしておかなくては。
We need to be in contact
to report anything,
no matter how trivial it is...
犯人を見つけ出すまではな。
Until we find the suspect.
うん。
Ｂの２番テントにいると思う。
Well, I think she's in Tent B-2.
今　シズネ先輩は　トントンを診てる。
Shizune is treating Tonton.
足を　ひどく
くじいちゃったみたいで。
Seems like a bad leg sprain.
手を怪我するよりは　マシだがな。
Well, that's better
than injuring a hand.
戦場へは戻れそうなのか？
Will they be able to
rejoin the battle?
そうね
手を怪我したわけじゃないから→
I think so...
Tonton can still weave signs,
since the hand is uninjured.
印は結べるし。
I see... That's good.
そうか　よかった。　ところで→
By the way...
サクラ　ついでに　腕の傷を
もう一度診てもらっていいか？
Sakura, would you mind taking
a look at my arm one more time?
まだ　少し痛むんだ。
うん。
It hurts a little.
Sure...
じゃあ　こっち来て座って。
You can sit over there.
ぐあっ！
♪～
な…　なんでわかった？
How did you know?!
Pigs don't have hands!
ブタに手はないんだよ！
しゃんなろ～！
Shannaro!
((そうね
手を怪我したわけじゃないから→
Tonton can still weave signs,
since the hand is uninjured.
(印は結べるし))
Tonton... is a pig?!
トントンって　ブタのことだったのか！
《ゼツ：カマかけたな　こいつ！》
She tricked us! Smart alec!
So, you're the murderer!
犯人って
あんたのことだったのね！
（ゼツ）ぐわぁ！
それにしても　どうやって
ネジさんのチャクラのまま→
Tell me... How were you able
to recreate Neji's chakra?!
変化できたの？
これは　どういう術？
What kind of jutsu is it?!
Explain or you'll get another one!
説明しないと　もう一発よ！
僕の変化の術は　忍一だよ。
My Transformation Jutsu
is the best.
I may not be the only who
has infiltrated this place.
ここに潜り込んだのは
僕一人とは限らないかもよ。
《これって
ヤマト隊長のレポートどおりなら…》
If this is just like
Captain Yamato's report...
((項目　寄生分身についてか。
Note... Regarding Parasitic Clones.
Kisame Hoshigaki was originally
thought to have been taken down
「干柿鬼鮫は　雷影とキラービーにより
処理されたとのことだったが→
by the Raikage and Killer Bee...
But it appears he survived,
変わり身の術であろう
寄生分身とやらで→
having switched places
with a parasitic clone
成り代わり　生きていたもよう。
or something that is a type
of Transformation Jutsu.
チャクラを真似る変化であるため
気づくのは難しく→
Because this transformation also
replicates the target's chakra,
it is difficult to detect.
五影会談において
暁　ゼツが　突然　体から出現。
At the Five Kage Summit,
Zetsu of the Akatsuki suddenly
emerged from other people's bodies.
(チャクラを吸い取るという」))
He had absorbed chakra...
《そして　こいつの　この変化。
そうか！》
And this guy's transformation...
I get it!
あんた　吸い取った　相手のチャクラを
そのまま利用して→
You are able to manipulate
the chakra that you absorb.
You can transform your chakra
into your victim!
同じチャクラに変化できるのね？
そうでしょ？
Isn't that right?!
There's too many of them!
((数が多すぎる！
(こいつ　チャクラを吸い取るのか))
You're absorbing chakra!
《こいつ　鋭い女だな》
She's a smart woman!
W-Well... I wonder about that...
さ…　さぁ　どうだろうな？
どれほど　変化で己を隠せても
ウソを隠すのは下手なようね。
You may be able to
camouflage yourself,
but you're not very good
at lying, are you?
どうした？
今　すごい音がしたぞ！
What happened?!
Did you hear that loud
sound just now?!
あっ　何だ？　そいつ！
Who's that?!
すぐに　本部に
連絡したいことがあるの。
I have to contact HQ immediately!
Please take care of this guy!
こいつ　お願いします！
重い荷を運びすぎだよ　トントン。
You've hauled too many
heavy loads, Tonton.
ブー。
≪どうした！？
≪サクラが　危急の用件で！
What happened?
Sakura has an emergency!
Lady Shizune, reporting!
≪シズネ様へ　報告があります！
しっかり出しとけよ。
次　俺らが見張りだぜ。
Empty it all out!
We're on guard duty next.
I must have a bigger bladder
than you.
お前より　出は　いいよ。
水面の波紋の大きさを比べてみろ。
Look at the big ripples I made!
The ripples are...
波紋の大きさはな。
Don't forget to piss either, Tetsu!
テツ　お前も絞り出しとけよ。
長くなるぜ。
It's going to be a long night.
つうか　テツ　後ろに立つな。
Hey Tetsu!
Don't stand behind me.
気が散って
出るもんも出なくなんだろ。
You're distracting me,
and nothing's coming out.
How about if I make you
bleed instead?
（テツ）ならさ　赤いの出すか？
代わりによ。
H-Hey?!
お…　おい！？
まただ！
It happened again!
There are reports from
every sector
各地の連絡班から次々に→
that our comrades are being ambushed
one after another!
仲間が闇討ちされてるという
情報が入ってきている！
現場は　大混乱だ。　敵が見えない！
There's confusion everywhere!
We don't know who the enemy is!
（シカク）どういうことだ？
夜襲の動きは　なかったはずだ。
What's going on?!
A night raid is supposed
to have been ruled out!
On top of that, we added security
and positioned Sensory-type ninja...
それに　防御を張り
感知タイプを置いていながら→
なんで　敵が見つけられない！？
Why can't we detect the enemy?!
毒か　何かか？
Is it some kind of poison?
死体の状態は！？
What's the condition of the corpse?!
All of them have external wounds!
（いのいち）皆　外傷が　あるそうだ。
物理的なものだ。
They're physical attacks!
幻術で　連合の忍を
操ってる以外に　ないな…。
No doubt they're controlling
Allied shinobi with genjutsu.
イタチか！？
Could it be Itachi?
（青）俺たち感知部隊からも
感知されない距離に隠れたうえ→
Uchiha Itachi is
the only one I know
who would be undetectable
by my Sensory Unit,
yet still be able to manipulate
with genjutsu from afar.
幻術で操れるようなヤツは
うちはイタチくらいだ。
これだけの広範囲の各場所を
細かく同時に操れるのは→
But this is impossible for even Itachi...
controlling minds simultaneously,
over such a wide area,
with such precision.
うちはイタチでも　無理だ！
待て！　医療部隊から連絡だ。
Hold on!
We just got word from
the Medical Corps!
敵の正体は→
The enemy looks to be...
White Zetsu transformed
into an Allied Force shinobi.
白いゼツが
連合の忍に　変化しているもよう！
He's able to mirror chakra imprints!
チャクラまで真似る術を使うようだ！
どおりで…。
That explains it...
So during the day battle,
どうやら　昼間の戦いで→
if one of our shinobi got
his chakra absorbed...
そいつに　チャクラを吸い取られた忍は
そっくりに変化されてしまう。
White Zetsu can transform
into him completely!
どうする！？　木ノ葉のシカク！
What should we do,
Shikaku of the Leaf?
こっちは
敵味方の見分けが　つかないうえ→
There is no way we can weed out
who is friend and who is foe!
How will we prepare
for the battle at dawn?
夜明けの開戦準備も　できないぞ！
If we don't find
the enemy immediately,
すぐに
敵を見つける対策をしなければ→
we'll not only lose precious time,
時間とともに
死者は　どんどん増え続けるぞ！
but our own men will
become casualties!
In the end, they could
end up killing each other!
しまいにゃ　仲間どうしで
殺り合うようになる！
So this is the power of White Zetsu...
（マブイ）これが
白ゼツの能力だったのですね。
The battle during the day
was simply to set up the night...
昼間の戦いは　この夜のための
準備ってことですね。
これが　敵の狙いだった。
This was the enemy's true motive.
《落ち着け…　俺は　冷静だ。
Calm down... I am rational.
If I calmly analyze the situation,
I will find a way!
冷静に分析さえすれば
必ず　道はある！
Sort and evaluate...
分析するんだ。
Review every piece of intel
relating to this war
この戦争のために叩き込んだ
すべての情報を紡ぎ→
and develop a counter strategy!
対策案を作るんだ！
But stay cool, and do it quick.
しかも　クールに素早く…。
Cool, but quick!
クールに　素早く！》
I want to overcome this cycle of regret and sadness
kurikaeshite kita ikutsu mo no koukai to kanashimi norikoe
to see what I'm really worth
jibun no kachi wo tashikamete mitainda
I'll shake off the voices around me
mawari no koe wo furi haratte
and push aside the surging crowd
muragaru hitonami kakiwakete
until I can touch that eternity I drew with you
anata to egaite kita eien ni fureru mate
even if I lose everything
tatoe subete ushinatte mo
I must move forward
susumanakya naranai
there's a door that only I can open
watashi ni shika hirakenai tobira ga aru
even if I'm hurt badly
fukaku kizutsuita to shite mo
I want to keep shouting
kono koe karashite
until I'm hoarse, I have a one and only love
sakebi tsuzuketai tatta hitotsu dake no ai ga aru
so I'll believe in this power welling up, and I'll stand
so waki agaru chikaraka wo shinjite tachiagaru
let it go, I'm beholden to this resilient life I've been given
let it go akiramene inochi moratta kari ga aru
scale mountains and valleys, for there's always something
yama ga aru tani ga aru norikoete moreba nani ga aru
live, for there's a future, there's a journey just for me
ikite ireba kono saki ga aru dare ni mo yuzurenai tabi ga aru
Next Episode
Don't let them touch you.
That's because they'll absorb
our chakra!
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Easier said than done...
How are we going to take them down
without touching them?
美空ひばりです。
I sent out a messenger owl.
では　最後まで
ごゆっくり　お楽しみください。
The sealing corps should arrive
shortly to seal up this mine.
So we just have to wait until then?
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "White Zetsu's Trap"
White Zetsu's Trap
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Just how many of them are there?